Russell Brady

PHONE: +353 87 1647913 EMAIL: RUSSELLBRADY456@GMAIL.COM

WEBSITE: HTTPS://RUSSELL-BRADY.GITHUB.IO/PERSONAL_WEBSITE

Summary

A full stack software engineer with 2 years' experience working on backend applications using Spring Boot and Kotlin/Java and on frontend SPA written using Vue.js and JavaScript. Strong problem-solving skills with a keen interesting in the process of taking business requirements, architecting a solution and implementing. A huge advocate for test-driven development (TDD) and for testing in general.

Skills / Languages / Frameworks

Proficient in Java, Kotlin, SQL, HQL and JavaScript languages. Working knowledge of python. Strong knowledge of Spring Framework, Vue.js, Hibernate ORM, Postgres, MySQL, Snowflake, Azure Service Bus.

Working day to day with Gradle, Docker, Azure, Git, Jira and Confluence.

Experience

Full Stack Software Engineer - Sep 2019 – Present ClarusONE Sourcing Services, LLP

- Working closely on the large-scale refactoring of a legacy server-side rendered application to a restful application which is used for sourcing pharmaceuticals.
- Heavily involved in the design and build of a greenfield Vue.js SPA as we incrementally migrate the monolith from server rendered application to restful application.
- Have led the design and development of numerous large new features, providing value to the business in the multi-millions.
- Designed and implemented a number of spring boot microservices from the ground up.
 Examples include a commenting service which provided a commenting capability to various features in the main application, and a reporting service with which the main application interacts with using an azure message bus to send events which were then stored in snowflake for analytics team to consume.
- Implementing backend functionality using Spring Boot and Hibernate ORM to interact with PostgreSQL and Snowflake data sources. Strong knowledge of Spring MVC, Spring IOC, Spring Transactions, Spring AOP and Spring Security modules.
- Currently leading an effort to reduce pre-existing tech-debt in the system such as reducing N+1
 queries to increase performance and re-architect some poorly modelled parts of the
 application.

Software Developer Intern - Apr 2018 – Sep 2018 **Synchronoss Technologies Ireland**

- Worked on the development of a white label email Android application as part of a small agile team of 4 people.
- Followed the MVVM android architecture and used the retrofit http client to interact with the backend and room persistence library for local persistence of data.

- Tasked with designing and developing numerous features in the app. Implemented dynamic solutions so that the needs of individual customers could be tailored for.
- Tasked with increasing unit test coverage throughout the app, resulting in an increase in code coverage and a reduction in technical debt in the project backlog.

QA Analyst Intern - Jun 2017 - Sep 2017 Synchronoss Technologies Ireland

- Worked on the development of a white label email Android application as part of a small agile team of 4 people.
- Followed the MVVM android architecture and used the retrofit http client to interact with the backend and room persistence library for local persistence of data.

Education

BSc in Computer Applications - 2015 – 2019 **Dublin City University – First Class Honours – Placed 2nd Overall**

3rd Year Project (Skin Condition Classification App using Deep Learning)

Designed and developed a Web app and Android app to classify skin conditions using Convolutional Neural Networks as part of a 2-person team. Awarded DCU president's award for Innovation upon completion of the project. Tech used: Java Android development, Python Flask web development, python machine learning (Keras/Tensorflow), AWS Deployment.

4th Year Project (Augmented Reality App for Technical Graphics)

Designed and developed an augmented reality learning app for technical graphics as an individual final year project. Accepted into EdTech conference to present the project and speak on the projects possible impact in technology enhanced teaching and learning. Tech used: Java Android development, Google ARCore/Sceneform augmented reality technology, Node.js backend, MySQL database.

Cnoc Mhuire Secondary School - 2010 – 2015 **Granard, Co. Longford** - **Leaving Certificate** - 555 points

Awards and Achievements

- Winner of the 2018/2019 Prof. Tony Moynihan Award for the best Final Year Project in B.Sc. In Computer Applications.
- Awarded DCU President's Award for Innovation for designing and developing a skin condition classification app as part of a two-person team which helps to self-diagnose skin conditions.
- Awarded best paper award for literature review titled 'From Monolith to Multilith: Software Systems Design Implications' as part of 4-person team out of 41 teams. Currently pushing to publish the paper in an IEEE conference next March.
- Invited to present at EdTech 2019 for designing and developing augmented reality application for teaching technical graphics and to talk on its possible impacts in teaching through augmented reality.
- Placed second in the class in 3rd & 4th year of college out of a pass list of over 100 students showcasing high achievement and consistency throughout the year.
- Awarded student of the year award in leaving cert out of a year of approximately 90 students for high achievement and excellence in school.